I am establishing a country.
I now call this land, Mount Liang.
You will act as Song Jiang's mistress.
I have made love to Deng Li Hua.
They have established their perch.
Our fight is not over.
The author for this script remains at large.
It seems you have an idea who this author is.
Ma Gui has a daughter.
Her name is Po Xi.
The people's pleas ought to be your orders.
We call this, the mandate of Heaven.
Yang Zhi, the Blue-faced Beast.
They raised the price of salt,
and cornered Chao Gai.
Qinglian Temple.
[Anqiu]
[Finale]
[Ji Ren Mei, Brothel maid]
Cao Zheng!
[Cao Zheng, Brothel proprietor (Ally)]
- How are you, old friend?
- Lu Zhi Shen.
Sir Yang Zhi, the sun has already risen.
So bright...
I see you have recovered your appetite.
But you must eat more to remain lively.
Lively, is it?
Some folks cannot even acquire food.
You must not waste any of it.
My life no longer has meaning.
What is it?
Does this scare you?
Do you fear swords?
My apologies.
Yang Zhi!
Ah, if it isn't Lu Zhi Shen.
We meet again, Yang Zhi.
Won't you spar with me, Yang Zhi?
Cao Zheng.
You have given me a roof and meal.
Why must I fight my savior?
When I mentioned your strength,
he insisted on testing the Blue-faced Beast.
I am quite confident in my skills.
I have never once lost while in Kaifeng.
So he says.
It is my loss. Forgive me!
But of course.
I am indebted to you.
If not for your generosity,
I'd have been beast-food by now.
Let us raise a toast together.
Liquor is how us men apologize, right?
You must understand, Yang Zhi.
He is simply an honest fool.
No harm in that.
I shall accept your offer.
Drinks, at this early hour?
Sorry to cause a commotion, Ji Ren Mei.
Yang Zhi, there is something
I would like you to see.
Is this...
Like a wasteland, no?
Even the Devil himself would avert his gaze.
Another village, gone.
"Another"?
Then you've witnessed
a similar scenery before?
I have.
I could not do a thing.
Do you realize you carry an honorable sword?
The village had long been ravaged.
No bandits remained, either.
I am once again too late.
What was that?
Does someone remain?
Answer me.
Are you alright?
Where are your parents?
What, we had stragglers?
Lucky day.
You despicable scum.
Who the hell?
Filthy men carry filthy swords.
Are there any left alive?
I have vanquished the bandits.
Survivors!
The bandits have left.
You may rest easy.
[Zhou Jin, Village Chief]
You, stranger.
Has our village somehow wronged you?
You have killed so many.
Those bandits will now return.
They will kill every last one of us.
If you had let them be,
they would cease their killings.
They would take our women, and leave us.
For bandits do not consecutively plunder
the same village.
Wait.
Do you not care if your villagers are killed?
Do you not care that your women
and belongings are stolen from you?
Then will you remain here,
and protect us from the next attack?
You have agitated the bee's hive.
You have made this village a battlefield.
Sir.
Is that how you wish to lead your lives?
I have protected this village
from the Mount Erlong bandits in my own way.
Does this child have no more relatives?
His parents were killed. He has no one else.
The village cannot look after him.
Abandon the boy as you see fit.
What cruelty.
You will abandon a mere child?
We must do away
with such sympathies to survive,
and live another day.
Can you truly call that living a life?
Yes. I can.
Impoverished as it may be.
To live does not mean evading death.
Yes. I hear you.
This boy desires to live.
Surely you jest.
Can you not see?
This boy wishes to live...
more than anyone in this village.
Welcome back.
Who is this child?
Ji Ren Mei, please try and calm him.
He fears even my very face.
Children do not care for me.
As such, I do not know how to handle them.
Yang Zhi, he does not fear your face.
It is the blood which scares him.
I see.
I understand.
Do not fear.
You are a man, are you not?
We have the strength to fight.
We can save our people
who are oppressed by those in power.
This fortress shall be a perch
for those who save the weak.
For those who look to the same blue skies.
I now call this land, Mount Liang.
What did Chao Gai write?
He pleads me to join him at Mount Liang.
He fears I am in grave danger.
I suspected as much.
You know of this supposed danger?
Indeed.
I sense someone is watching my every move.
Perhaps you are simply tired.
Tired?
Yes, you may be right.
Yet I am told those from Qinglian Temple
are hidden in plain sight.
My suspicions may very well be on the mark.
Why not join him at Mount Liang?
It is not yet my time.
I appreciate the message, Deng Li Hua.
Please tell Chao Gai
to give me a bit more time.
I shall.
You have been tailing me all day.
What is so fun about that, Qing?
I have a theory I'd like to prove.
I believe I cannot marry Deng Li Hua,
because of your circumstances.
What circumstances?
Brother, you are no mere clerk for Yuncheng.
Calm yourself.
I only ask for a proper explanation.
Oh, bother.
Your stubbornness has not changed.
Even as a child,
you hated leaving questions unanswered.
I believe you have another side to you.
What "other side"? Do tell.
I cannot so openly speak on it.
Yet you spoke to Deng Li Hua
as though she were no mistress.
I can only assume
she is aware of your secret.
Will you speak out against this nation?
I only ask that you tell me your plans.
Fine. I shall tell you everything.
And you promise not to run?
Do you think I would?
No. My apologies.
Now go on.
Yes, Brother.
Qing.
These parts are getting dangerous.
Take care on your way home.
You as well.
Qing.
I am planning no mere uprising.
I am plotting a rebellion.
Sir Han! We were waiting!
Evening, ladies.
- Don't look down on...
- I will lay waste to Mount Erlong!
Skipping the preamble, I see.
Do you have a plan?
I will infiltrate the Mount Erlong bandits,
and take the head of their leader, Deng Long,
as well as several others.
That should get them to surrender.
These are basic war strategies.
You plan to barge through the front gates?
Indeed. Lu Zhi Shen and myself
will suffice for manpower.
I must simply find a way in...
I see.
- Cao Zheng.
- Yes?
Now is the time to prove your use.
- Me?
- Yes.
Yang Zhi.
Can you act like a drunkard?
Yes, can you?
Here. Take a sip.
- Go on.
- Yes, go on.
- Drink!
- Eat!
Watch your step, sir.
You can't be getting injured here...
Yang Zhi, sir.
You must act like a proper drunk.
- How?
- Look to thy neighbor.
Bring me the booze.
- I decline.
- If you insist.
The hell are you?
I am the proprietor of a local brothel.
My name is Cao Zheng.
Hey, I know this bloke.
Why'd you bring us men?
We want the women!
My patrons here drunk themselves stupid,
and killed many of your men, or so I heard.
You!
What? You know something?
This is him. I remember the mark.
Follow us, you bastards!
[Mount Erlong]
Unhand me!
[Deng Long, Leader of the bandits]
These are the murderers?
Yes, sir.
I shall reward you for apprehending them.
Thank you, sir.
Now, for your sentences.
We will flay you alive, one finger at a time.
You will beg for a swift death.
Come down.
Then we will cut your arms and legs,
leaving only your body to flail about,
as we slowly gouge out your stomach.
Why won't he come down?
You blabber on,
yet refuse to unsheathe your sword.
Words alone shall not kill us.
You, bald monk!
Do you wish to repeat yourself?
Fine. I will kill you myself.
It is nice to see you again, Song Jiang.
Likewise. It has gotten harder
to meet like this.
Has Deng Li Hua proven to be of use?
She is a beautiful woman.
The perfect accessory
to camouflage oneself as corrupt.
I have come today, seeking your wisdom.
To what ends?
It has gotten difficult
to protect our salt roads.
Why not increase our number of guards?
One can try to disguise a soldier,
but the equipment they carry
make their identities obvious.
It will only make our cargo more suspicious.
The people from Qinglian Temple
will surely catch on.
Indeed.
Perhaps I may have to bribe
some officials myself,
though we will ultimately operate at a loss.
The smuggled salt...
Smuggling...
Undercover...
Perhaps we can ask Gongsun Sheng for his aid.
I see.
The covert Zhisi Squadron.
They excel at disguising themselves.
I will pass the request
to Chao Gai as well.
Thank you, Song Jiang.
Have you been left out again?
Yes.
They've come to discuss important business.
Why can his mistress listen in,
but not myself?
- His mistress?
- Yes, his mistress.
Her name is Deng Li Hua.
Deng Li Hua...
I have made love to Deng Li Hua.
Song Jiang won't tell me a thing.
I am always left in the dark.
You called, Lu Zhi Shen?
I leave this place to you, Yang Zhi.
- Pardon?
- Mount Erlong.
We cannot allow these bandits
to roam free, and plunder villages.
You must take control,
and correct their ways.
What?
You say I should lead these bandits?
Who else could train such ruffians
into men with real ambition?
For you, that is possible, Yang Zhi.
[Enforcing the Way in Heaven's Name]
Li Fu, what bothers you so?
The head of Mount Erlong has been killed.
A new leader has been appointed in his place.
And who is this new leader?
Yang Zhi.
Now that is troublesome indeed.
First, Chao Gai. And now, Yang Zhi.
These bandits are not like the others.
What makes them different, if I may ask?
Bandits are united by money alone.
Yet these men crave no riches.
They are united by their ambitions.
No, impossible.
Which is what makes them
especially troublesome.
Though their ambitions may start small,
they will one day
dream of a country of their own.
At which point we are no longer fighting
a gang of bandits, but a nation.
It is not the bandits we need to defeat.
But their very ambitions.
I do feel Mount Liang and Mount Erlong
were conquered in similar ways.
This country is rotten to its core.
And yet, this nation persists.
A rotting finger is no reason
to end one's life.
You must simply cut that rot away.
We will kill the rotting officials.
We will extinguish any ember of a rebellion.
We cannot allow men like Lin Chong
and Lu Zhi Shen to roam free.
There is a captain named Zhu Tong
who was transferred to Yuncheng by Gao Qiu.
He is apparently training a man there
in the way of swordsmanship.
Indeed.
The ambidextrous clerk in Yuncheng,
who deftly utilizes his different scripts.
You know him?
I have already sent Wang He's men to him.
They are looking into his background
as we speak.
We are observing his daily routines.
From what he eats,
to how often he uses the restroom,
to his type in women.
You refer to the man named Song Jiang,
do you not?
Song Jiang!
I apologize for the wait.
Chao Gai, why have you come here?
Because you refuse to come to Mount Liang.
You are the leader of Mount Liang.
As are you.
Do you realize the danger
you put yourself in?
The Qinglian Temple are scouring Yuncheng.
The streets are filled with your posters.
Like you are one to speak.
What?
You are also a target of Qinglian Temple.
I cannot leave for Mount Liang yet.
I killed ten spies from Qinglian Temple
on my way here.
They suspect you, and your people.
Yet you still insist on remaining here?
Chao Gai.
I have come to express my concerns in person,
as it seems my letters did not suffice.
Song Jiang, come to Mount Liang with me.
Chao Gai.
I plan to leave, and go on a journey.
What?
I wish to see the wider world,
and decide how best to rebuild this country.
See the wider world?
Yes.
You fool!
That is what spies are for.
They are our eyes and ears.
A leader cannot roam the lands,
and put himself in danger.
That is how I wish to establish a country.
Must you see everything to build a nation?
Such an endeavor
would take hundreds of years!
If the Emperor now
sets foot outside his castle,
and witnessed the state of this country,
would he continue
to play ball as he does now?
Song Jiang.
I can only protect you now,
because you are still within my reach.
Go on a journey,
and I will be unable to send aid.
Leave the roaming to your spies.
It is one thing to hear a recounting.
It is another to see it for myself.
I wish to truly feel our people's suffering.
No emperor would do such a thing!
Which is why countries fall to ruin!
If you perish,
the soul of Mount Liang dies with you.
Can't you see that?
"Enforcing the Way in Heaven's Name".
Those writings are your very heart.
If you earnestly believe that to be true,
then you must let me be myself, Chao Gai.
I will embark on this journey.
I'm sorry.
Song Jiang!
Lu Zhi Shen also worried for you.
He left you a souvenir,
in hopes he would help.
At the very least,
take him with you.
You damn fool!
Wu Song?
Sir Song Jiang...
Where have you been?
I have been conversing with the earth.
What did it have to say?
It said to live, and struggle.
To live, and fight.
You've hurt your fists once again.
You need not tell me.
All our men sent to Song Jiang have died,
have they not?
Yes, sir.
He has practically incriminated himself.
Shall we kill him?
Killing Song Jiang will solve nothing.
We must recruit Ma Gui to our side.
She will give us the intel we desire.
Chivalrous bandits will prove difficult
to break apart, sir.
Perhaps I shall start by tossing in a pebble.
Even water birds who fly in perfect sync,
scatter away in chaos...
at the sound of a thrown stone.
Meaning?
I believe this Ma Gui has a daughter
named Yan Po Xi.
We shall have this girl...
see misfortune.
I entrust my younger brother to you.
It is a memento of our mother.
I was told to offer this to my wife,
but I do not see marriage in my near future.
Instead, I shall gift it to you.
This is all I can do for you both now.
Thank you, I am honored.
Show my younger brother
this sign of my approval.
Say, has he told you of his childhood?
No, not at all.
Then allow me to indulge you.
You are soon to become family, after all.
I promise to find much happiness with him.
This is a story of Qing
when he was just six years old.
I had gone to get him
after my swordsmanship lessons,
only for him to greet me with a glare.
Of course, I asked what was wrong.
Qing answered
by clutching his rear with both hands.
Your people no longer have any enemies.
Though I know killing them
will never ease the pain in your hearts.
I plan to change this Mount Erlong.
My men will work to protect
the surrounding villages.
Then you will become a bandit?
Deng Li Hua, will you make sure
I do not succumb to that fate?
You are asking this of me?
You cannot remain nameless forever.
From this day forth,
you will be called, "Yang Ling".
The Yang family are descendants
of the great hero, Yang Ye.
Do not look so surprised.
Though we are not tied by blood,
we are connected by something else.
Ambition.
Listen well, Yang Ling.
We are father and son, tied by our ambitions.
Speak, my boy.
Yang Ling.
Once more.
Yes.
That's right.
That's your name.
Sir Yang Zhi...
Ji Ren Mei.
Will you be this child's mother?
I shall.
And I will keep you on your honorable path.
So that you may never become a bandit.
Thank you.
I cannot believe it.
A man like myself, now a father.
Has anything changed with Song Jiang?
- I know nothing.
- Please, tell me anything at all.
I am simply his attendant.
You must know something.
You are also hiding secrets, Mother.
You, Song Jiang... everyone.
- You do not need to know.
- Yes, I know nothing.
So what about Song Jiang am I to report?
- Po Xi!
- And Father!
This grave, you, Song Jiang...
Lies. It's all lies!
Do you wish to know the truth, Po Xi?
You are...
Song Jiang, you will oversee this river.
Sir, I cannot swim.
How can a man not...
Ow, ouch!
What is the commotion?
Wu Song?
Tang Niu Er is up to no good.
It's in his eyes.
His eyes? Is that all?
Ouch!
I cannot allow his suspicious gaze
to go unattended.
Wu Song is usually correct
about these things.
Tang Niu Er, what are you hiding from us?
My firsts are like boulders.
Resist, and you will crack.
I...
I sense you are attempting to lie.
Tell us the truth, or you die.
I love Yan Po Xi!
Pardon?
I only wished to tear her heart
away from you, sir.
What have you done?
I told Yan Po Xi a lie.
What lie?
Forgive me, sir!
I told her you planned to marry Deng Li Hua.
What have you done?
I apologize for the commotion.
Please, carry on.
Song Jiang's life is in danger.
In truth, he leads the bandits
gathered at Mount Liang.
Your mother and father were both his spies.
Are you beginning to see the full picture?
Deng Li Hua is a spy sent in from Kaifeng.
She was sent to end Song Jiang's life.
Her beauty has tricked Song Jiang.
He will no longer listen to our words.
But my mother, she...
Ma Gui did not wish to get you involved.
You are the one closest to Song Jiang.
I want you to protect him for us.
I will do anything.
If it will protect Song Jiang, anything.
Then please, accept this.
They are moon cakes, laced with oleander.
I...
I long for Sir Song Jiang.
- I...
- I feel similarly.
Your eyes, they are filled with sorrow.
I suspect we both had a rough upbringing.
The weak are given no chance in this world.
Yet Song Jiang promises
to bring about change.
I believe he will make it happen.
Deng Li Hua!
Song Qing?
What brings you here?
Since it will soon be known,
I shall tell you.
Deng Li Hua and I are to get married.
Married?
I expect you are surprised.
Deng Li Hua was acting
as my brother's mistress after all.
Why?
Why would he tell such a lie?
I do not know myself.
My brother will speak about it
when he returns home.
Deng Li Hua? Deng Li Hua!
Deng Li Hua!
Was this...
You poisoned her.
Was it?
Po Xi?
Po Xi, are you here?
Brother...
Deng Li Hua has died.
That woman killed her!
She was poisoned...
Po Xi.
I poisoned her.
Why?
I was told Deng Li Hua
was a spy sent to kill you.
Who would tell such a ridiculous lie?
Qinglian Temple.
I was told the medicine...
would save you.
Po Xi, my enemies are the ones
who gave you this medicine.
Sir Song Jiang.
Who are you really?
I...
Even now, I know nothing...
Po Xi. Po Xi!
I was so...
very far from you.
Po Xi.
Po Xi!
I wanted to keep you away from danger.
That is why I told you nothing.
Song Jiang...
Deng Li Hua was killed.
Brother.
She murdered my love.
If only I arrived a moment earlier...
You both...
were supposed to become happy.
Song Jiang, we must leave at once.
If I had arrived a moment earlier...
Tang Niu Er will speak of this
to the local officers.
Song Qing.
I will take all the blame for this incident.
You must head to Mount Liang.
Song Jiang...
What a fool I am.
As if I could change a nation as I stand now.
I could not even hear the voice of Po Xi,
who was right at my side.
The fault lies with myself alone.
What will you do now?
I will embark on a journey.
A journey?
Charge!
Make way!
Stay in formation.
- Charge!
- Yes, sir!
[Song Jiang]
You fool.
Song Jiang.
Return to us alive!
Calm yourself, Chao Gai.
Mount Liang is still too far
for a man like myself.
[Finale - FIN]